Kidney function, liver function,
testosterone...
I don't know how you did it,
but you have essentially aged 40 years
in the last seven weeks.
Wow. Really?
We had a meth addict in here this morning
who was biologically younger
than you are, and he's 58.
MySpace guy.
So what is going on?
Uh...
It's this cloud service configuration,
- I've been stuck on it for over a week.
- Wow.
I'm a good programmer.
I mean, it's the only thing I am good at.
I mean, last year,
I threw a Frisbee and I chipped my tooth.
Oh, that's more of a dental issue.
Yup, okay, I...
The point is, I learned Ruby on Rails
over a weekend when I was 17.
I should be able to learn cloud, I have to.
May I give you my professional opinion,
as your doctor?
You should have taken that $10 million
from Gavin Belson, okay?
But regrets will kill ya,
so try not to dwell on it.
I tried to tell you.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
Outside help?
No, we're not getting any outside help.
It's a week until TechCrunch, Richard.
We can't wait any longer.
Richard, look at the board.
Okay, cloud architecture is just a giant
turd that is clogging up our pipes.
We have to call in a plumber to fix it.
Okay, I hate that metaphor,
but Erlich is right.
Gilfoyle and I finished
the distribution services days ago
and we're just sitting
around waiting for you.
- I can solve it.
- Richard, you're a fucking rock star, okay?
You just don't know cloud,
this tiny, little, shitty area,
which is becoming super important,
and in many ways is the
future of computing.
That sort of went south on me,
but you understand what I'm saying.
I've already talked to Peter Gregory
about insourcing a consultant.
I've made contact with a programmer
whose cloud architecture
is supposed to be insane.
They call him The Carver.
The Carver?
That Black Hat guy who apparently hacked
into the Bank of America
and took down their entire system,
that The Carver?
We should get him if we can.
(SIGHING)
Okay, we can talk to the guy, but, I
mean, he's really gonna have to sell me.
JARED: Six months ago,
these guys had $35 million
and Series B financing.
Now The Carver's here doing teardown.
He's basically moving their carcass
to the cloud.
ERLICH: Don't touch anything.
Failure is contagious.
I think that's him.
(TYPING)
Excuse me, Mr. Carver?
(SNICKERING) Yeah, uh, people refer to me
as The Carver,
but no one actually calls me that.
It's, uh, what people call a screen name.
You know. I'm Kevin.
Okay, Kevin, um, we're from Pied Piper,
we spoke earlier.
- Yeah, so you guys are fucked, huh?
- No. No, we're not fucked.
Yes, we are totally fucked.
We have a live demo in one week
and our cloud is in the shitter.
- That's accurate.
- Wait, are you Richard?
Yes, I am.
Yeah, your, uh, algorithm is solid.
It's a really good schema.
Okay, thanks.
I did think you'd be younger.
What are you, 25?
I'm 26.
Yikes.
Uh, so I have a Model UN thing on Monday,
but maybe I could burn through your gig
over the weekend.
Mmm. You think you can do our whole job
in two days?
I know I can do it in two days.
I pound Mello Yello, Oreos and Adderall
and I don't sleep until I'm done.
- Okay.
- (SCOFFING)
But you know what? I also have an offer
to do some migration at Gittawonk
this weekend.
It's, uh... It's kind of chill, and
frankly, their tech's a little stronger.
Whoa. What? What?
You think Gittawonk's tech
is stronger than ours?
I'm sorry, I don't remember reading
in PandoDaily
that Gavin Belson and Peter Gregory
were fighting over Gittawonk.
No one offered $10 million
to acquire Gittawonk.
Yeah, I agree with Richard,
you should come work for us.
- What... No...
- What's it gonna take, a blow-job?
Because Richard will suck the
dick right off of your pelvis.
(LAUGHING)
Now, you make me laugh, shaggy man.
All right, I'm in. I'll
see you guys Friday.
(TYPING)
RICHARD: Okay.
- (WHISPERING) Well done.
- (WHISPERING) Yeah.
Excuse me.
Hi, um, would you guys be interested
in buying some candy so you can
send my church group to camp?
Nope.
RICHARD: Erlich, come on.
ERLICH: $100 says there's no church.
Whole thing's a scam, little scumbags.
They're just children.
Looks like Gilfoyle and his lady Satanist
are back from the airport.
Can you imagine what kind
of shit-show this one's gonna be?
He says that she has an Amy Winehouse vibe.
What does that mean?
All tatted-up and nowhere to go?
- Hooked on OxyContin?
- Decomposing?
Oh. Oh, okay, that was dark.
Gentlemen, this is Tara.
- Hey.
- Tara, this is the fellas.
Jared, Dinesh, (MISPRONOUNCING)
Erlich and Richard.
- It's Erlich.
- Oh, it's great to finally meet you guys.
Hi.
- (TARA GIGGLING)
- GILFOYLE: All right.
Hmm.
Jesus, where did he
get Amy Winehouse from?
I mean, I'd have sex with that
if you hose the Gilfoyle off of her.
It's weird having a girl in the house.
There's a very strange energy.
Hmm.
Hello... Kevin.
(CHUCKLING) Okay, Richard,
I just need you to approve Kevin's fee.
I got Erlich to sign
and you just sign right there.
$20,000 for two days.
You know who else thought
my price was too high?
- BitRaptor.
- Who?
Exactly.
Great. Peter Gregory is on his way out
of town so I'm gonna hustle out there
and get him to co-sign these
and the check,
and I'll be back as soon as I can.
- Well, go.
- Thank you.
You okay over there?
You have any questions...
Yeah, one question.
Cool. Shoot.
Why do you keep your lips
pressed so tight together
when you're not talking?
'Cause they're like white.
It looks uncomfortable.
(SCOFFING)
(TYPING)
(MOUTHING SILENTLY)
Hey, guys.
Hey, Kevin, um,
so how did you bypass
Bank of America's network security?
I want details.
My lawyers told me
I'm not allowed to discuss it.
Totally get it. That's baller.
- Hey, babe? You're up.
- Hmm.
(WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY)
- TARA: All right, I'm gonna go have a shower.
- GILFOYLE: Mmm-hmm.
- Uh, what was that?
- What?
Tara just whispered something to you
and then she looked at me in a weird way.
No, she didn't.
Yeah, she did.
What's up?
Do you know what compression is?
It's when someone takes pleasure
in seeing their loved one gratified
by another person.
Sexually. It's the opposite of jealousy.
It sounds like it's the opposite of normal.
Why are you telling me about this thing?
(CLEARING THROAT) As shocking as this is...
Tara is attracted to you.
Come again?
Yeah, freaked me out, too, at first.
I don't like the "at first" part at all.
What are you saying?
Since I abide by the maxim,
"Do what thou wilt,
that is the whole of the law,"
if you want to fuck my girlfriend,
I'm okay with it.
Jesus Christ, man, I could barely stand
next to you when you're in your towel.
I don't want to have a threesome with you.
I'm not talking about a threesome.
Listen, I don't even have to be in the
room, unless that's better for you.
Okay, no, I don't...
Right, so we're all settled then?
- Yep.
- Do you need parking validation?
No, I, uh, used Lyft.
So I'll Lyft it back.
Why don't I have Peter's car take you home?
He's not using it,
we're shipping off to Arallon tomorrow.
- Arallon?
- Yeah, the island Peter's building.
What's the... The red line?
That's the International Date Line.
The island's built right on it
so the western half can celebrate
the first New Year's on Earth,
then the next day,
they walk over to the eastern half
and celebrate the last New Year's on Earth.
But if you can walk,
why does he need the car on the island?
Peter's not really big on walking.
So I'll just have the guys
pull it up front for you.
Great.
(CHUCKLING)
Driverless car.
COMPUTER: (BEEPING) Select destination.
Hi, um... I'm going to 5230
Newell Road, Palo Alto...
Route guidance calibrated.
Distance to destination: 4.6 miles.
Buckle up, please.
- (BEEPING)
- Okay. (CHUCKLES)
Enjoy your ride.
(JARED CHUCKLING)
You'?
Tara wants to have sex with you? You sure?
Yeah, Gilfoyle just told me, to my face.
He told you that Tara wants to copulate
with someone else in the house
other than him
and that someone is you, Dinesh?
Yeah, that's...
You know, you seem confused by this
but for a different reason than I am.
Don't you think it's weird
that Tara wants some strange
and she chooses you over me,
the logical person in the house?
Okay, I see where we are ending up on this.
Thank you for your time.
Wait, are you sure that
she didn't ask Gilfoyle
for a Danish and maybe you misheard her?
You're probably right,
she just wanted to fuck a Danish.
Wait, you just built all
the indexes on the fly?
Yeah, of course.
Okay, well... Well, then what's that?
The key value store.
Tuples.
(WITH A FOREIGN ACCENT)
Speak English?
(SIGHS)
You're kind of doing that
lip thing again there, buddy.
No, I'm not.
Stop looking at my lips.
(BEEPING)
Destination override. New destination.
1 Gregory Drive. Arallon.
Distance to destination: 4,126 miles.
Enjoy your ride. (BEEPING)
Um, what's happening?
Uh...
I'm sorry, what... Mr. Car?
Hey. Tara and I are going
to a Satanic baptism.
You wanna come?
Stu Burns decided to walk
the left-hand path with us.
The database administrator for Yahoo
is becoming a Satanist?
We're everywhere.
Hey, Erlich, are you coming? Dinesh is.
He is?
- (PHONE RINGING)
- This is Monica.
Hi, Monica, it's Jared.
Uh, quick question...
Jared, I can't talk right now.
One of our assistants
has been confusing the eastern,
western time zones of
Arallon on work orders.
Now a bunch of important things
are happening a day early.
Peter is going to be furious
when he finds out.
- He's going to make that noise.
- (CELL PHONE BEEPING)
Oh, shit, that's him on the other line.
I've gotta go.
Oh, wait, Monica, I just...
Hi, Peter.
(DEEP GUTTURAL SOUND)
Hello, Monica?
Um, car? Mr. Car?
Uh, excuse me.
Arallon is an island, so how are we, um...
Oh, no, no! No, no, no, no.
Stop. Let me out.
Um...
Mmm. Um...
Uh, that's not good.
Oh, no! No!
Excuse me, please!
- Please honk. Please honk.
- (DOOR SHUTTING)
No, no, no, no. No, no, no.
No, no. Please. Please.
Oh, no, that's not good.
Okay, Donald, stay calm.
(LOUD METALLIC THUDDING)
103 hours to destination.
Entering sleep mode.
- What? No!
- Enjoy your ride.
Okay, stay calm. Stay calm.
Wait, my phone.
No bars. No bars. No bars. No bars.
- (SCREAMING)
- (SHIP HORN BLARING)
"We bring thy garden, o mighty Lucifer,
"the fragrances which abound
therein, vapors of..."
(WHISPERING)
What the fuck are we doing here?
Look at these fucking people.
"...through this, the black flame
of Satan thou walkest in Hell.
"The gates are flung wide
"and thy passage is heralded
by the deathless cries
"of his guardian beasts.
"Breathe of his breath,
o brother of the night
"and nourish his waning brain.
- "From the despair..."
- (WHISPERING) I just figured it out.
It all makes sense.
Figured what out?
Why Tara might be into you more than me.
She's attracted to ugliness.
- (WHISPERING) on, fuck you.
- (WHISPERING) No, think about it.
This is the life that she chooses, right?
She's attracted to unattractiveness.
Look at all these ugly people
and Gilfoyle and now you.
That's ridiculous.
I'm way more attractive than you are.
- No, you're not.
- Way better looking.
By no metric could you possibly
be considered more attractive than me.
You're saying that every woman
in the entire world
would think you're more
attractive than I am?
- Yes. Unless they're completely fucked up.
- That's fuck...
Damn it.
You doing okay there?
Yep, yeah.
Fine, just, you know,
it's big orchestration stuff,
a lot of moving parts.
Nothing you need to worry about.
You just focus on the cloud.
I'm here if you need me.
You know what? Uh...
I know it's not what we hired you for,
but I am actually having a little trouble
with the data replication
in the persistence layer.
Move over.
- Uh-huh.
- (EXHALES DEEPLY)
Oh, Christ.
- I'm much more handsome than you are.
- No, my face is completely symmetrical.
You know what my nickname
was when I was a kid?
- What?
- Pakistani Denzel.
You look nothing like him.
Denzel Washington has a beautiful smile.
You look ridiculous.
Hail Satan, it is done.
- ALL: Hail Satan.
- ERLICH: Hail Satan, it is...
It's done.
Well, thanks for coming, everyone.
Brother Jason was kind enough
to furnish this week's food.
It's Chick-fil-A.
I know, they're on the Christian right,
but darned if that chicken isn't good.
- I think the Dark Lord would understand.
- Also... Ugh. A reminder.
- (WOMAN CHUCKLING)
If you parked in the Sav-On parking lot,
they do tow.
Well, I didn't know if you wanted
original Oreos or Double Stuf
so I went a little nutty and I got both.
How's it, um...
- KEVIN: Fuck. Fuck.
- (SIGHS)
- Kevin?
Hello?
(WHIMPERING) Fuck.
What are you doing down here?
I did it again, I did it again.
- Did what?
- I did it again.
KEVIN: (MUMBLING) No.
What is this?
Did you overwrite the data schema?
Why would you do this?
You don't ever do this!
That's exactly what they said
when I was working at BofA.
Working at BofA? I thought you hacked in.
KEVIN: No.
I was a consultant
at the retail banking services.
I crashed their entire system.
It took a team of seven engineers
more than a week
to comb through all the code
and find my mistake.
And the only way that
I ever avoided being sued
was by agreeing to never tell anyone
that I worked there.
Oh, fuck.
Oh, fuck, what?
I just told you. Now I
could get in trouble.
Trouble?
You just skull-fucked my whole system.
I am going to punch you in the fucking...
We don't like sacrifice goats or anything.
We're not like
the Order of the Golden Dawners, you know.
- ERLICH: Yeah.
- (TARA CHUCKLING)
Richard, are you okay?
Um... Mmm...
Dinesh, uh, we may have a slight problem.
The Carver just carved
up our entire platform.
What the fuck?
Yeah, the database layers,
the application layers,
even the chef scripts are fucked.
The little fucker must have hacked
into the DDL tables like he did with BofA.
He didn't hack into BofA.
He was consulting there at the time,
when he took down the system by accident.
- KEVIN: Oh, you told them too?
- What the fuck?
Richard, why would you let that
little fetus access the DDL?
Because I thought
that fetus was better than me
and so did you and everybody
and you just, you pressured me
into hiring him...
Yes, Richard, for the cloud,
to deploy the cloud.
So that you could do what you do best
and concentrate on everything else
which the fetus just fucked up.
You need to drag this little shit stain...
You hear that?
(BANGING ON TABLE)
out from under this table
and have him go through
every single line of code with you
to unfuck it while it's still unfuckable.
I should not have eaten
all of that Satanist chicken.
RICHARD: Okay, and with this one here,
did you delete it
or just move it?
Hello? Kevin.
Maybe. I don't know.
What? What does that mean?
What's wrong with you, man?
I can't focus. I'm out of Adderall.
Where's that Jared guy?
He was getting my refill.
That's actually a really good question.
I don't know where he is.
(JARED SINGING SOFTLY)
The Carver's Adderall prescription.
I hope that's not a problem.
- (PHONE BEEPING)
- Dead battery.
That's a problem.
I need to lay down.
What? No! (SCOFFING)
You said you could code
for 48 hours straight.
That's like your thing.
Yeah, how the fuck do you think I do that?
Adderall.
Well, we don't have any.
It's really bright in here.
Who takes Adderall anymore?
KEVIN: Half the kids in Palo Alto.
Hey-
Any of you guys currently on Adderall
and, uh, you know, want to make $50?
(EXHALING) Oh, boy.
What do you mean, it's not Adderall?
It's Adderall!
I know what Adderall looks like.
It's not Adderall.
(SIGHING)
Uh...
Excuse me. Caleb?
There's been some kind of mistake.
What you sold me was not actually Adderall.
So maybe we could...
Do you think you could get me
some real Adderall?
Yeah, yeah, of course.
Um...
I could do that or, um...
I can give you some of this.
- Ow!
- (CHILDREN LAUGHING)
Okay, I'm gonna...
You're gonna do what, bitch?
Call the cops on me?
Tell them you got the wrong
illegal drugs from a kid?
You dumb piece of shit.
Get the fuck out of here.
- Uh, you...
- Run!
- All right, I'm running.
- Keep running!
Stupid... (GROANING)
Richard, what's wrong?
Have you been crying?
Hey! Which one was it?
It was Church Candy, wasn't it?
You just brought piss to a shit fight,
you little cunt!
Ow!
(GROANING)
CALEB: No, no, no!
Now you get in your fucking house
and you get me five Adderall
or I'll slit your fucking throat!
You understand?
I'll kill your mother!
I'll rape your father!
I'll curb-stomp that little face so hard
that your teeth will go
flying, you little shit!
Now go! Go! Go! Go!
- Get me five Adderall, right now!
- Okay! I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
- Hi.
- Tara.
- Hello.
- Hi.
First of all...
So, um...
I have thought about it. A lot.
To be honest, elements of this arrangement
still trouble me.
However, I have not had
a lot of sexual experiences.
So I feel it may be foolish
to turn this down.
So as long as Gilfoyle is not in the room
and I can verify that the door is locked
then I have concluded that,
yes,
I would love to have
sexual relations with you,
Tara.
Yeah.
Uh, what are you talking about?
Gilfoyle told me.
I know you want to have sex with me.
Gilfoyle?
Would you come in here for a second?
Um...
Um... (SNICKERING)
Did you tell Dinesh that
I want to have sex with him?
No.
Oh, wait, yeah, I totally did.
I forgot about that.
I was really high. I was
just fucking with him.
Did he believe me?
Uh...
Did you just present yourself to my woman?
(STAMMERING) Uh...
Oh, this is outstanding.
Oh, my God, that is so mean of you!
Look at how cute he is.
He's adorable. You're adorable.
Don't call me... It's very emasculating.
What kind of fucking idiot
listens to what Gilfoyle has to say?
Okay, Tara, here's what it is.
If you can tell me to my face
that you seriously find Dinesh
more attractive than me,
then and only then will I concede defeat.
What?
And our regression test is...
- (BEEPS)
- Done.
Yes. It's clear, we all test out.
(SIGHS)
- The system's stable again.
- Thank God.
Now we can move on to the next module
and I can forget you ever existed.
Can you do me a favor?
Don't tell anyone I cratered this bad.
I won't tell anyone I hired you
if you won't tell anyone you worked here.
Oh, the BofA deal. Got it.
(KEVIN SIGHS)
Well, I'm gonna call my mom
and have her pick me up.
Your mom?
Oh, by the way, you owe me $20,000.
What a dick.
You have to talk to Jared about that.
Where is Jared?
(LOUD RUMBLING)
(GROANING)
(APPROACHING HUMMING SOUND)
Excuse me. Can you help me?
COMPUTER: Obstacle averted.
Resuming operations.
Please be careful.
- Please be careful.
- (DISTANT) Please be careful.
(WIND HOWLING)
Okay.
(JARED SINGING)
(VOICE TREMBLING)
- (SCREAMING)
- (SHIP HORN BLARING)